I'm a blogger, a filmmaker and a butcher,
أنا مدوٌن و صانع أفلام وجزار.
and I'll explain how these identities come together.
وسأشرح كيف اجتمعت تلك الهويات معاً.
It started four years ago,
بدأت القصة قبل أربع سنوات،
when a friend and I opened our first Ramadan fast
عندما بدأت أنا وصديقي بصيام أول يوم رمضانٍ
at one of the busiest mosques in New York City.
في واحدٍ من أكثر المساجد ازدحاماً بمدينة نيويورك.
Crowds of men with beards and skullcaps were swarming the streets.
جمعٌ من الرجال بلحى وقبعات يحتشدون في الطرقات.
It was an FBI agent's wet dream. (Laughter)
إنه الحلم المثالي لوكالة التحقيق الفيدرالي.(ضحك)
But being a part of this community, we knew how welcoming this space was.
كوننا جزءاً من هذا المجتمع، عرفنا مدى مستوى الترحيب في هذا الفضاء.
For years, I'd seen photos of this space being documented
لسنوات رُأيت صوراً موثقة لهذه المساحات
as a lifeless and cold monolith,
على أنها بلاروح ،وكأنهت كتلة متراصة باردة،
much like the stereotypical image painted of the American Muslim experience.
أشبه ما تكون بصورة نمطية رُسمت عن تجربة المجتمع الأمريكي المسلم.
Frustrated by this myopic view,
أصابتنا هذه النظرة قصيرة المدى بالإحباط،
my friend and I had this crazy idea:
فخطرت ببالنا أنا وصديقي فكرة مجنونة:
Let's break our fast at a different mosque in a different state
بأن نفطر في مساجد مختلفة وفي ولايات مختلفة
each night of Ramadan
في كل ليلة رمضانية
and share those stories on a blog.
ومن ثم مشاركة تلك القصص في المدونة.
We called it "30 Mosques in 30 Days,"
وأطلقنا عليها "30 مسجداً في 30 ليلة،"
and we drove to all the 50 states
مررنا خلال الرحلة بخمسين ولاية
and shared stories from over 100 vastly different Muslim communities,
واستمعنا إلى أكثر من 100 قصة للمجتمعات الإسلامية المختلفة جدا،
ranging from the Cambodian refugees in the L.A. projects
بدءاً من اللاجئين الكمبوديين في مشاريع لوس أنجلوس
to the black Sufis living in the woods of South Carolina.
إلى صوفيين من السود يعيشون في غابة تابعة لولاية كارولينا الجنوبية.
What emerged was a beautiful and complicated portrait of America.
فكان أن ظهرت صورة جميلة ومعقدة لأمريكا.
The media coverage forced local journalists
أجبرت التغطية الإعلامية الصحفيين المحليين
to revisit their Muslim communities,
لإعادة النظر في مجتمعاتهم الإسلامية،
but what was really exciting was seeing people from around the world
ولكن ما كان مثيرا حقاً هو رؤية الناس من جميع أنحاء العالم
being inspired to take their own 30-mosque journey.
وقد ألهموا بالقيام برحلات ال30 مسجدا بأنفسهم.
There were even these two NFL athletes
حتى أن اثنين من محترفي دوري كرة القدم.
who took a sabbatical from the league to do so.
تقدما بطلب إجازة من الاتحاد للقيام بتلك الرحلة.
And as 30 Mosques was blossoming around the world,
حين ازدهرت فكرة "30 مسجداً" حول العالم.
I was actually stuck in Pakistan working on a film.
كنت حينها عالقاً بالعمل على إنتاج فيلم في باكستان.
My codirector, Omar, and I were at a breaking point with many of our friends
كنت أنا ومدير الإنتاج المشارك "عمر" في موضع خلاف مع العديد من أصدقائنا
on how to position the film.
على كيفية وضع الفيلم.
The movie is called "These Birds Walk,"
أُطلق على الفيلم اسم "تلك الطيور تسير،"
and it is about wayward street kids
وهو فيلم عن أطفال الشوارع التائهين.
who are struggling to find some semblance of family.
الذين يكافحون للعثور على بعض مظاهر الأسرة.
We focus on the complexities of youth and family discord,
نركز في هذا الفيلم على التعقيدات التي تواجه الشباب وتفكك الأًسر.
but our friends kept on nudging us to comment on drones and target killings
لكن أصدقاءنا ألحوا بالإشارة للقتلى المستهدفين من قِبل طائرات بدون طيار
to make the film "more relevant,"
ليكون الفيلم "أكثر ترابطاً"،
essentially reducing these people who have entrusted us with their stories
على أساس أن نقتصر قصص هؤلاء الناس الذين وثقوا بنا في روايتها
into sociopolitical symbols.
على رموز اجتماعية سياسية.
Of course, we didn't listen to them,
بالطبع ، لم نستمع لهم،
and instead, we championed the tender gestures of love
وبدلاً من ذلك، ناصرنا إيماءات الحب الرقيقة
and headlong flashes of youth.
وبتهور أيضاً ناصرنا ومضات الشباب.
The agenda behind our cinematic immersion was only empathy,
إن الغاية من وراء انغماسنا السينمائي كان التعاطف لا أكثر،
an emotion that's largely deficient from films
عن المشاعر التي تنقصنا بشكل كبير في الأفلام
that come from our region of the world.
القادمة من منطقتنا من هذا العالم.
And as "These Birds Walk" played at film festivals and theaters internationally,
بما أن "تلك الطيور تسير" عُرض في مهرجانات ومسارح الأفلام عالمياً،
I finally had my feet planted at home in New York,
أخيراً حطت قدمي في منزلي بنيويورك،
and with all the extra time and still no real money,
ومع كل الأوقات الإضافية المبذولة، ومن دون مقابل مادي.
my wife tasked me to cook more for us.
كلفتني زوجتي أيضاً بالطهي لنا.
And whenever I'd go to the local butcher to purchase some halal meat,
وكلما ذهبت إلى جزار محلي لشراء بعض اللحم الحلال،
something felt off.
كان هنالك شعور يراودني.
For those that don't know, halal is a term used for meat
بالنسبة لأولئك الذين لا يعرفون، حلال: هو مصطلح يُستخدم للحوم
that is raised and slaughtered humanely following very strict Islamic guidelines.
الماشية التي تُربى وتُذبح بأيدي بشر ملتزمين جدا بالتعاليم الاسلامية.
Unfortunately, the majority of halal meat in America
للأسف، فإن غالبية اللحم الحلال في أمريكا
doesn't rise to the standard that my faith calls for.
لا يرقى إلى المستوى الذي يدعو إليه معتقدي.
The more I learned about these unethical practices,
وكلما علمت بشيء حول هذه الممارسات غير الأخلاقية،
the more violated I felt,
أشعر بمزيد من الانتهاك،
particularly because businesses from my own community
لا سيما وأن الشركات من مجتمعنا
were the ones taking advantage of my orthodoxy.
تتكسب من وراء معتقدي.
So, with emotions running high, and absolutely no experience in butchery,
لذلك، مع تأجج المشاعر ومن دون أي خبرة في الجزارة على الاطلاق،
some friends and I opened a meat store
قمت مع بعض الأصدقاء بفتح محل جزارة.
in the heart of the East Village fashion district.
في قلب حي قرية الموضة الشرقية
(Laughter)
(ضحك)
We call it Honest Chops,
وأسمينا المحل بـ"القطع الصادقة"،
and we're reclaiming halal by sourcing organic, humanely raised animals,
ونقوم باستصلاح ما هو حلال من مصادر عضوية، وحيوانات تُربى على أيدي بشر،
and by making it accessible and affordable to working-class families.
مع جعل تلك المنتجات سهلة المتناول، وبأسعار معقولة لأسر الطبقة العاملة.
There's really nothing like it in America.
إذ لا شيء مشابه لمثل هذا في أمريكا.
The unbelievable part is actually that 90 percent of our in-store customers
الجزء الذي لا يُصدق هو أن 90% من عملاء متجرنا
are not even Muslim.
ليسوا بمسلمين حتى.
For many, it is their first time interacting with Islam
وللكثيرين، فإنها المرة الأولى التي يحتكون فيها مع الإسلام.
on such an intimate level.
بمثل هذا المستوى من الحميمية.
So all these disparate projects -- (Laughter) --
لذلك كل هذه المشاريع اليائسة--(ضحك)--
are the result of a restlessness.
ما هي إلا نتيجة هاجس مؤرق.
They are a visceral response to the businesses and curators
تلك المشاريع ما هي إلا استجابة غريزية ضد الشركات والمحتكرين
who work hard to oversimplify my beliefs and my community,
لتلك المشاريع لتبسيط معتقداتي ومجتمعي،
and the only way to beat their machine is to play by different rules.
وأن الطريقة الوحيدة للتغلب على سيطرتها هو أن تلعب بقواعد مختلفة.
We must fight with an inventive approach.
يجب أن نناضل بمنهجية إبداعية
With the trust, with the access, with the love that only we can bring,
مع شيء من الثقة، مع التمكين، ومع الحب وهو الشي الوحيد الذي نستطيع جلبه،
we must unapologetically reclaim our beliefs
يجب أن نستعيد معتقداتنا بدون إية اعتذارات
in every moving image, in every cut of meat,
في كل صورةٍ متحركة، في كل قطعة لحم،
because if we whitewash our stories for the sake of mass appeal,
لأننا إذا حاولنا تبرئة قصصنا وتلميعها من أجل جذب اهتمام شامل.
not only will we fail,
فإننا لن نفشل فقط،
but we will be trumped by those with more money and more resources
بل سيستعملنا من يملكون المزيد من المال والموارد
to tell our stories.
لسرد قصصنا.
But the call for creative courage is not for novelty or relevance.
ولكن الدعوة إلى الشجاعة الخلاقة ليست دعوة للحداثة أوتبيان الأهمية.
It is simply because our communities are so damn unique and so damn beautiful.
ببساطة لأن مجتمعاتنا فريدة من نوعها وجميلة جداً.
They demand us to find uncompromising ways to be acknowledged and respected.
إنهم يطالبونا بإ يجاد طرق لا مساومة عليها لأجل الاعتراف بهم ولاحترامهم
Thank you.
شكراً
(Applause)
(تصفيق)